<data>

    <!-- Source:
        http://swartz-report.mit.edu/docs/report-to-the-president.pdf
    -->
    <event start="Sep 25 2010 17:00:00 EST" end="Sep 26 2010 04:00:00 EST"
           durationEvent="true" title="First anomalous JSTOR downloads"
        >
      JSTOR engineers notice an extremely large number of requests for
      downloads originating from MIT.  They observe 450,000 articles from
      560 journals downloaded during this period.
        </event>

    <event start="Sep 26 2010"
        title="JSTOR closes access to offending IP class"
        >
      The Class C network within MIT's allocation is blocked by JSTOR from
      accessing its resources.  Access is restored after discussion between
      MIT Libraries and JSTOR resolves that an unknown network visitor was
      responsible and unlikely to return.
        </event>

    <event start="Oct 09 2010"
        title="Second anomalous JSTOR downloads"
        >
      A network visitor downloads about 8,000 articles, wreaking havoc
      amongst JSTOR services but caught quickly by already watchful engineers.
      </event>

    <event start="Oct 09 2010 23:15:00 EST" end="Oct 12 2010"
           durationEvent="true"
           title="JSTOR blocks a broad swath of MIT addresses"
        >
      In response to the second attack, JSTOR blocks an entire Class A
      network, covering a significant part of campus, from its services,
      lifted in part because this massive download attempt was caught quickly.
      </event>

    <event start="Nov 28 2010" end="Jan 6, 2011" durationEvent="true"
        title="Third and final batch of JSTOR downloads"
         >
      Swartz initiates a less obvious, long-running download job by setting
      up his laptop and a disk drive in an MIT infrastructure closet.  JSTOR
      catches on to this attempt a month later and discovers it resulted in
      obtaining 4.3 million articles.  Swartz has made about 4.8 million
      downloads in total, about 80% of JSTOR's database.
      </event>

    <event start="Dec 26, 2010" end="Dec 27, 2010" durationEvent="true"
        title="JSTOR informs MIT"
        >
      JSTOR engineers contact MIT over email and request assistance,
      having potentially discovered where on campus the much larger
      download came from.  They try twice but fail to reach anybody
      as all but a skeleton crew are on furlough at the end of the year.
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 3, 2011" end="Jan 4, 2011" durationEvent="true"
        title="MIT responds to JSTOR"
        >
      MIT see the messages when furlough ends and responds the next day
      that identifying the culprit based on the information gleaned so
      far is unlikely.
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 4, 2011 03:00:00 EST" end="Jan 4, 2011 08:00:00 EST"
        durationEvent="true" title="Network engineers discover laptop"
        >
      MIT IS&amp;T network engineers try to find the exact location of
      the computer associated with the IP address.  One sees the
      cardboard box covering a cable connected to the network switch and
      discovers the laptop underneath.
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 4, 2011 09:45:00 EST"
           title="MIT, Cambridge Police notified">
      IS&amp;T management notify MIT Police of the intrusion, and minutes
      later officers arrive and are posted in the hallway.  At the same time,
      network engineer staff connect to the same switch to observe network
      traffic flowing to the laptop.  Photographs are taken; the MIT Police
      call in their colleague from the Cambridge Police Department who
      normally works with them on computer-related crimes.
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 4, 2011 11:00:00 EST"
           title="Cambridge detective and Secret Service agent arrive">
      The Cambridge detective is part of the New England Electronic Crimes
      Task Force which includes both state and federal officers.  The
      detective brought in the special agent of his own choosing, not
      by any outside request.
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 4, 2011 15:00:00 EST"
           title="Camera installed in closet">
      In order to attempt to identify and apprehend the culprit, a
      surveillance camera is installed in the closet and everything
      else is restored to the way it was found.  Officers and staff
      depart.
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 4, 2011 15:30:00 EST"
           title="Suspect stops by to swtich drives">
      Someone stops by not long after to swap out the current disk
      drive with a new one, taking the old with.  He is captured on
      video but not recognized.  Still photos are distributed to MIT
      Police.  They arrive too late to the closet to apprehend him.
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 5, 2011"
           title="Federal criminal investigation opened">
      The U.S. Attorney's Office opens its criminal investigation, directed
      by Assistant U.S. Attorney Stephen Heymann, head of the Internet and
      Compuer Crimes Unit within the USAO.
    </event>

    <event start="Jan 6, 2011 12:30:00 EST"
           title="Suspect removes all equipment from closet">
      Someone stops by, with a bike helmet covering his face, to
      remove the laptop and hard drive, taking them with as he
      departs.  The person responsible for monitoring the status
      of the network port is not on campus but notifies co-workers
      and police that the laptop is disconnected.  They arrive too
      late to the closet to apprehend him.  However, they note that
      the laptop re-appears on the Student Center network later
      that afternoon, in the offices of the student computing group.
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 6, 2011 14:00:00 EST"
           title="Police identify suspect and arrest him">
      An officer on patrol by car sees Swartz cycling past and matches
      his clothing and backpack to descriptions and stills of the
      suspect he knew was being sought.  After making a stop, Swartz
      refuses to cooperate and runs.  With assistance, two officers
      and the special agent catch up to him in a parking lot and
      handcuff him.
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 6, 2011 15:00:00 EST"
           title="Suspect identified as Aaron Swartz">
      Swartz is taken to the Cambridge Police Department for booking
      where he is identifies to the police.  He calls his friend to
      arrange bail money, and an attorney arrives shortly to complete his
      bail paperwork, departing with Swartz.  He is charged with two
      felony counts of breaking and entering for his recorded incursions
      into the network closet. (time imprecise)
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 6, 2011 17:00:00 EST"
           title="Laptop confiscated">
      Network engineers, MIT Police, and the special agent search
      the student computing group's offices and locate the laptop and
      hard drive, confiscating them for evidence. (time imprecise)
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 9, 2011"
           title="MIT Counsel learns about Swartz">
      The MIT Office of the General Counsel searches for information
      on Aaron Swartz on the Internet and learns about his background.
      (time imprecise)
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 9, 2011"
           title="MIT adopts neutrality">
      "Very early in this post-arrest preiod, MIT decided to 'remian
      neutral,' as between the government and Aaaron Swartz, in the
      investigation and eventual prosecution.  Initially this meant
      simply that MIT would not take a public position on the prosecution.
      Throughout the following (almost) two years, MIT’s decisions were
      mostly guided by this posture of neutrality." - page 52 (time imprecise)
      </event>

    <event start="Jan 10, 2011"
           title="JSTOR access at MIT severly reduced">
      Before these events, JSTOR and MIT were in talks to increase barriers
      to access JSTOR content.  The efforts were expedited and put into place
      not long after Swartz is arrested.  JSTOR can only be accessed from
      certain workstations in the libraries.
      </event>

    <event start="Mar 15, 2011"
           title="MIT Counsel learns about prosecution">
      The lead prosecutor telephones the MIT OGC to inform them that
      the government is actively prosecuting Swartz. (time imprecise)
      </event>

    <event start="Jun 3, 2011"
           title="Swartz settles with JSTOR">
      Swartz turns over his copy of the JSTOR data, assuring that there
      are no other copies in existence and none to be released to the
      public.  With that assurance, JSTOR drops any further pursuit of
      civil charges.  In addition, Swartz paid $26,500 to JSTOR, $1,500
      for damages, and $25,000 for attorneys' fees and costs.
      </event>

    <event start="Jun 21, 2011"
           title="Federal lead prosecutor discusses investigation with MIT">
      During a phone call with the lead prosecutor, the OGC is informed
      of the state of the investigation, which is that an indictment might
      come down based on the prosecutor's supervisors' decision of how
      to proceed.  His stance is to give MIT information as it pertains
      and arrives.  MIT concludes that MIT's opinions were unlikely to have
      an effect on the prosecution as their views appeared to have already
      been taken into account.  Also, if JSTOR considered the matter closed
      and yet prosecution was proceeding, MIT's opinions would have no
      impact either.
      </event>

    <event start="Jul 14, 2011" end="Sep 12, 2012" durationEvent="true"
           title="Federal indictment returned by grand jury">
      A federal grand jury in Boston hands up an indictment charging Swartz
      on four felony counts, one for wire fraud and three for violating the
      Computer Fraud and Abuse Act.
    </event>

    <event start="Jul 19, 2011"
           title="Swartz arraigned in federal court">
      The indictment is unsealed.  This is the first MIT learns of it through
      a phone call from the prosecutor to MIT's Office of the General Counsel.
      Swartz was informed the day before, and his attorney arranged for him
      to be present, after which he was, by normal procedure, arrested and
      taken to lockup for processing.
    </event>

    <event start="Jul 19, 2011"
           title="Demand Progress petition begins">
      Demand Progress begins a campaign in support of Swartz, ultimately
      garnering 35,000 signatures on its petition.
    </event>

    <event start="Jul 19, 2011"
           title="JSTOR issues press release">
      JSTOR issues a press release describing its involvemnt in the case
      against Swartz while noting that the pursuit of criminal prosecution
      is the government's choice, not JSTOR's, further noting that all
      civil matters are concluded and it has no interest in making it
      an ongoing legal matter.
    </event>

    <event start="Nov 6, 2011" end="Mar 12, 2012" durationEvent="true"
           title="State indictment issued">
      In Superior Court for Middlesex County, an indictment against
      Swarz for six felony counts is issued: two counts of breaking and
      entering with the intent to commit a felony, three counts of
      accessing a computer without authorization, and one count of larceny.
      This is the court used for "more serious" cases, instead of the
      Cambridge District Court.
    </event>

    <event start="Nov 17, 2011"
           title="MIT learns of state indictment">
      From the Cambridge District Attorney's Office press release; MIT
      is not involved in this case in any material fashion.
      </event>
    
    <event start="Mar 12, 2012"
           title="State charges dismissed">
      Because the state cannot obtain vital evidence from the Boston
      General Attorney's Office as its held for the federal case, the
      state charges are all dismissed.
    </event>

    <event start="Sep 12, 2012" end="Jan 11, 2013" durationEvent="true"
           title="Superseding federal indictment returned">
      A second grand jury in Boston hands up a superseding indictment
      with 13 felony counts, two for wire fraud and 11 for violating
      the CFAA.
    </event>

    <event start="Oct 5, 2012"
           title="Defense files motions to suppress evidence">
      Swartz's defense team files five motions to suppress evidence
      and one to dismiss the indictment, arguing that the government
      and MIT violated the fourth amendment and privacy expectations.
    </event>

    <event start="Nov 16, 2012"
           title="Government files opposition to motions to suppress">
    </event>

    <event start="Dec 14, 2012"
           title="Hearing for motions to dismiss and suppress scheduled">
      A hearing is scheduled for January 25, 2013.
    </event>

    <event start="Jan 11 2013"
        title="Suicide"
        link="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz"
        >
      Aaron Swartz is found dead in the Brooklyn, New York apartment he
      shared with his partner.  He was 26.
        </event>

    <event start="Jan 13 2013"
        title="MIT panel convened"
        link=""
        >
      MIT President Rafael Reif convenes a panel to review MIT's involvement
      in the events leading up to Swartz's death, to culminate in a public
      report on its findings.
        </event>

    <event start="Jul 26 2013"
        title="MIT panel's report released"
        link="http://swartz-report.mit.edu/docs/report-to-the-president.pdf"
        >
      The MIT review panel releases its findings.
        </event>

</data>
