<data>
    <event starts="Sat May 20 1961 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="'Bay of Pigs' Invasion"
        >
        </event>
    <event starts="Wed May 01 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600" ends="Fri May 31 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald moves to New Orleans"
        >
        Oswald moves to New Orleans, and finds employment at the William 
        B. Riley Coffee Company. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 320
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri May 10 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="General Walker shot"
        >
        General Walker shot at in his home. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 319
        </event>
    <event starts="Wed Jun 05 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Kennedy, Johnson, and Connally met"
        >
        Decision for Texas trip made at meeting with Kennedy, Johnson, 
        and Connally at the Cortez hotel in El Paso Texas. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event starts="Wed Sep 25 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Veciana sees Maurice Bishop speaking to Oswald"
        >
        Antonio Veciana travels to Dallas for a meeting with Maurice 
        Bishop (A.K.A.David Atlee Philips). In the lobby of the 
        Southland building, Veciana sees Bishop speaking to a man 
        Veciana later identifies as Lee Harvey Oswald. ref. Last 
        Investigation, p 141.
        </event>
    <event starts="Tue Oct 01 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Reporter Arther Krock writes..."
        >
        Reporter Arther Krock, citing a dispatch from Vietnam reporter 
        Richard Starnes writes, "The CIA's growth was likened to a 
        malignancy which the very high official was not sure even the 
        White House could control any longer. If the United States ever 
        experiences an attempt at a coup to overthrow the government 
        it will come from the CIA and not the Pentagon. The agency 
        represents a tremendous power and total unaccountability to 
        anyone". ref. Last Investigation, p 422
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Oct 11 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Kennedy signs National Security Action Memorandum"
        >
        Kennedy signs National Security Action Memorandum (NSAM) #263 
        signalling his intention to withdraw troops from Vietnam.
        ref. JFK, CIA, Vietnam by Prouty, p xxiii.
        </event>
    <event starts="Wed Oct 16 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald begins job at Texas School Book Depository"
        >
        Oswald begins job at Texas School Book Depository. He reportedly 
        obtained it through a contact of Ruth Paine. 
        ref. Last Investigation, p 422.
        </event>
    <event starts="Wed Oct 23 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Ruth Paine noted Oswald purchased rifle"
        >
        Ruth Paine makes notation on her calender - ‘LHO purchase of 
        rifle.’ ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 293
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 08 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="SS Agent Lawson receives schedule of Texas trip"
        >
        SS Agent Winston Lawson is briefed and receives a tentative 
        schedule of Texas trip from SS Agent Roy H Kellerman who was 
        the agent in charge of arranging the timetable for trip and 
        responsible for motorcade route.
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 08 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Governor Connelly confirms trip"
        >
        Governor Connelly confirms trip to Dallas on November 21--22/63.
        ref. W.C
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 08 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald writes to Mr. Hunt"
        >
        Oswald writes to, "Dear Mr. Hunt, (Most likely Howard E. Hunt.) 
        I would like more information concerning my position. I am 
        asking only for information. I suggaestin that we discuss the 
        matter fully before any steps are taken by me or anyone else. 
        Thank you, Lee Harvey Oswald." ref. Last Investigation, p 423; 
        ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 324; 
        ref. Crossfire (Letter shown in full)
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 08 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald delivers note to Dallas FBI HQ"
        >
        Oswald delivers a note to Dallas FBI HQ where Agent James Hosty 
        is told to destroy it by Special Agent in Charge, Gordin Shanklin.
        ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 261
        </event>
    <event starts="Thu Nov 14 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="SS Agents Lawson and Sorrels test-drive route"
        >
        SS Agents Lawson and Sorrels drive route from Lovefield to 
        Trademart which went down Main street to Stemmons freeway.
        ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 15 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Motorcade route reviewed, unchanged"
        >
         Motorcade route reviewed but was unchanged. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event starts="Sat Nov 16 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Dallas Times Herald reports motorcade route"
        >
        Dallas Times Herald reported that the Presidential motorcade "apparently 
        will loop through downtown area, probably on Main street on its way 
        to Trade Mart". ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event starts="Sun Nov 17 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="FBI teletype calls to determine potential threat"
        >
        An FBI Teletype is received, directed to all field offices to contact 
        CIs (confidential informants) to determine whether a revolutionary group 
        was a potential threat to the president during his Dallas trip November 
        22 - 23. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 77
        </event>
    <event starts="Mon Nov 18 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="SS Agents Lawson and Sorrels verify motorcade timing"
        >
        SS Agents Lawson and Sorrels with Dallas police assistant Chief Charles 
        Batchelor drive motorcade route verifying that it could be driven in 
        45 minutes and was unchanged. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event starts="Tue Nov 19 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Newspaper published precise route"
        >
        Newspaper published precise route mentioning the turn into Elm into 
        Houston then onto the freeway. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event starts="Wed Nov 20 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Police officers witness mock target practice"
        >
        Two Dallas Police Officers witness a “mock target practice” going on 
        at the picket fence atop the knoll. They arrived in time to see the 
        partipants depart in haste, and only write a report of the incedent 
        subsequent to November 22. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 132
        </event>
    <event starts="Wed Nov 20 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Newspaper reports motorcade route on front page"
        >
        Newspaper reports motorcade route on front page. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event starts="Wed Nov 20 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Rose Cheramie warns of JFK assassination"
        >
        Rose Cheramie is thrown from a car, taken to hospital, and while there 
        tells doctors that JFK is going to be killed in Dallas.
        ref. Crossfire, p 401.
        </event>
    <event starts="Thu Nov 21 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Bundy signs key first draft of NSAM 273"
        >
        McGeorge Bundy, then assistant to President Kennedy, signs the key first 
        draft of NSAM 273, in contradiction to all previous Kennedy policy.
        ref. JFK, CIA Vietnam by Prouty, p xii.
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 11:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Young man with rifle in bag spotted on Elm St."
        >
        Julia Ann Mercer, drives down Elm street, her way is blocked by a green 
        Ford pickup truck. A young man removes a long paper bag, she can see 
        the outlines of a rifle in the bag, and he walks with it to the top of 
        the grassy knoll. She also sees the driver of the truck, whom she later 
        identifies as Jack Ruby, (before he shot Oswald). ref. Crossfire, p 18.
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 11:10:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Air Force One leaves Carswell AFB Fort Worth"
        >
        Air Force One leaves Carswell AFB Fort Worth for 13 min flight to Lovefield Airport.
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 11:30:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Motorcade leaves Lovefield Airport"
        >
        Presidential Motorcade leaves Lovefield Airport. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 11:45:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald left alone in TSBD"
        >
        Oswald is left on sixth floor of the TSBD as fellow workmates leave to 
        go to Lunch break. He yells, “Guys, How about an elevator?” And then 
        adding “Send one of the elevators back up”. ref. Conspiracy - Who 
        Killed Kennedy?, p106
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 11:50:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald seen near telephone in TSBD"
        >
        TSBD foreman Bill Shelley said he saw Oswald near the telephone on 
        the first floor. Conspiracy - Who Killed Kennedy?, p 107
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Jack Ruby seen in office with Wanda Walker"
        >
        Jack Ruby is seen sitting in an office at the Dallas Morning News by 
        newspaper employee Wanda Walker. ref. Crossfire, p 327
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Eddie Piper says he speaks to Oswald"
        >
        TSBD employee Eddie Piper said he actually spoke to Oswald, 
        “Just at twelve o’clock, down on the first floor”. 
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:10:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Unidentified cars seen cruising motorcade area"
        >
        Lee Bowers, a railway supervisor located in a tower behind the knoll 
        fence, sees a 1959 Oldsmobile cruise the area. And at 12:20pm, a 
        Black 1957 Ford also did the same and left. Then a third car, a 61 
        or 62 Chevrolet Impala entered the area, parked out of his sight near 
        the decorative masonry wall, then reappeared immediately after the 
        last shot. ref. Crossfire, p 75-76.
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:15:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald seen having lunch"
        >
        Carolyn Arnold sees Oswald eating lunch on the second floor lunchroom. 
        ”Oswald was sitting in one of the booth seats on the right hand side 
        of the room as you go in. He was alone as usual and appeared to be 
        having lunch. I did not speak to him but I recognized him clearly.”
        ref. Crossfire, p 49; Conspiracy - Who Killed Kennedy?, p 108
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:15:00 GMT-0600" ends="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:20:00 GMT-0600"
        title="TSBD sixth floor empty"
        >
        TSBD employee Bonnie Ray Williams leaves the sixth floor after eating 
        his lunch, he saw nobody ref. Crossfire, p 49; Conspiracy - Who Killed 
        Kennedy?, p 106
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:15:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Man with rifle seen at Western end of TSBD"
        >
        Witness Arnold Rowland observes man with rifle at the Westeren end 
        of TSBD. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 300
        </event>
    <event starts="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:18:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Man with seizure in front of TSBD"
        >
        A young man suffers some sort of seizure in front of the book depository.
        ref. Crossfire, p 42
        </event>

</data>