<data>
    <event start="Sat May 20 1961 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="'Bay of Pigs' Invasion"
        >
        </event>
    <event start="Wed May 01 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600" end="Sat Jun 01 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600" isDuration="true"
        title="Oswald moves to New Orleans"
        >
        Oswald moves to New Orleans, and finds employment at the William 
        B. Riley Coffee Company. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 320
        </event>
    <event start="Fri May 10 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="General Walker shot"
        >
        General Walker shot at in his home. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 319
        </event>
    <event start="Wed Jun 05 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Kennedy, Johnson, and Connally met"
        >
        Decision for Texas trip made at meeting with Kennedy, Johnson, 
        and Connally at the Cortez hotel in El Paso Texas. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event start="Wed Sep 25 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Veciana sees Maurice Bishop speaking to Oswald"
        >
        Antonio Veciana travels to Dallas for a meeting with Maurice 
        Bishop (A.K.A.David Atlee Philips). In the lobby of the 
        Southland building, Veciana sees Bishop speaking to a man 
        Veciana later identifies as Lee Harvey Oswald. ref. Last 
        Investigation, p 141.
        </event>
    <event start="Tue Oct 01 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Reporter Arther Krock writes..."
        >
        Reporter Arther Krock, citing a dispatch from Vietnam reporter 
        Richard Starnes writes, "The CIA's growth was likened to a 
        malignancy which the very high official was not sure even the 
        White House could control any longer. If the United States ever 
        experiences an attempt at a coup to overthrow the government 
        it will come from the CIA and not the Pentagon. The agency 
        represents a tremendous power and total unaccountability to 
        anyone". ref. Last Investigation, p 422
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Oct 11 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Kennedy signs National Security Action Memorandum"
        >
        Kennedy signs National Security Action Memorandum (NSAM) #263 
        signalling his intention to withdraw troops from Vietnam.
        ref. JFK, CIA, Vietnam by Prouty, p xxiii.
        </event>
    <event start="Wed Oct 16 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald begins job at Texas School Book Depository"
        >
        Oswald begins job at Texas School Book Depository. He reportedly 
        obtained it through a contact of Ruth Paine. 
        ref. Last Investigation, p 422.
        </event>
    <event start="Wed Oct 23 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Ruth Paine noted Oswald purchased rifle"
        >
        Ruth Paine makes notation on her calendar 'LHO purchase of
        rifle.' ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 293
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 08 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="SS Agent Lawson receives schedule of Texas trip"
        >
        SS Agent Winston Lawson is briefed and receives a tentative 
        schedule of Texas trip from SS Agent Roy H Kellerman who was 
        the agent in charge of arranging the timetable for trip and 
        responsible for motorcade route.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 08 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Governor Connelly confirms trip"
        >
        Governor Connelly confirms trip to Dallas on November 21--22/63.
        ref. W.C
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 08 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald writes to Mr. Hunt"
        >
        Oswald writes to, "Dear Mr. Hunt, (Most likely Howard E. Hunt.) 
        I would like more information concerning my position. I am 
        asking only for information. I suggaestin that we discuss the 
        matter fully before any steps are taken by me or anyone else. 
        Thank you, Lee Harvey Oswald." ref. Last Investigation, p 423; 
        ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 324; 
        ref. Crossfire (Letter shown in full)
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 08 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald delivers note to Dallas FBI HQ"
        >
        Oswald delivers a note to Dallas FBI HQ where Agent James Hosty 
        is told to destroy it by Special Agent in Charge, Gordin Shanklin.
        ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 261
        </event>
    <event start="Thu Nov 14 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="SS Agents Lawson and Sorrels test-drive route"
        >
        SS Agents Lawson and Sorrels drive route from Lovefield to 
        Trademart which went down Main street to Stemmons freeway.
        ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 15 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Motorcade route reviewed, unchanged"
        >
         Motorcade route reviewed but was unchanged. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event start="Sat Nov 16 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Dallas Times Herald reports motorcade route"
        >
        Dallas Times Herald reported that the Presidential motorcade "apparently 
        will loop through downtown area, probably on Main street on its way 
        to Trade Mart". ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event start="Sun Nov 17 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="FBI teletype calls to determine potential threat"
        >
        An FBI Teletype is received, directed to all field offices to contact 
        CIs (confidential informants) to determine whether a revolutionary group 
        was a potential threat to the president during his Dallas trip November 
        22 - 23. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 77
        </event>
    <event start="Mon Nov 18 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="SS Agents Lawson and Sorrels verify motorcade timing"
        >
        SS Agents Lawson and Sorrels with Dallas police assistant Chief Charles 
        Batchelor drive motorcade route verifying that it could be driven in 
        45 minutes and was unchanged. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event start="Tue Nov 19 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Newspaper published precise route"
        >
        Newspaper published precise route mentioning the turn into Elm into 
        Houston then onto the freeway. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event start="Wed Nov 20 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Police officers witness mock target practice"
        >
        Two Dallas Police Officers witness a "mock target practice" going on 
        at the picket fence atop the knoll. They arrived in time to see the 
        partipants depart in haste, and only write a report of the incedent 
        subsequent to November 22. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 132
        </event>
    <event start="Wed Nov 20 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Newspaper reports motorcade route on front page"
        >
        Newspaper reports motorcade route on front page. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event start="Wed Nov 20 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Rose Cheramie warns of JFK assassination"
        >
        Rose Cheramie is thrown from a car, taken to hospital, and while there 
        tells doctors that JFK is going to be killed in Dallas.
        ref. Crossfire, p 401.
        </event>
    <event start="Thu Nov 21 1963 00:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Bundy signs key first draft of NSAM 273"
        >
        McGeorge Bundy, then assistant to President Kennedy, signs the key first 
        draft of NSAM 273, in contradiction to all previous Kennedy policy.
        ref. JFK, CIA Vietnam by Prouty, p xii.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 11:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Young man with rifle in bag spotted on Elm St."
        >
        Julia Ann Mercer, drives down Elm street, her way is blocked by a green 
        Ford pickup truck. A young man removes a long paper bag, she can see 
        the outlines of a rifle in the bag, and he walks with it to the top of 
        the grassy knoll. She also sees the driver of the truck, whom she later 
        identifies as Jack Ruby, (before he shot Oswald). ref. Crossfire, p 18.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 11:10:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Air Force One leaves Carswell AFB Fort Worth"
        >
        Air Force One leaves Carswell AFB Fort Worth for 13 min flight to Lovefield Airport.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 11:30:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Motorcade leaves Lovefield Airport"
        >
        Presidential Motorcade leaves Lovefield Airport. ref. W.C.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 11:45:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald left alone in TSBD"
        >
        Oswald is left on sixth floor of the TSBD as fellow workmates leave to 
        go to Lunch break. He yells, "Guys, How about an elevator?" And then 
        adding "Send one of the elevators back up". ref. Conspiracy - Who 
        Killed Kennedy?, p106
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 11:50:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald seen near telephone in TSBD"
        >
        TSBD foreman Bill Shelley said he saw Oswald near the telephone on 
        the first floor. Conspiracy - Who Killed Kennedy?, p 107
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Jack Ruby seen in office with Wanda Walker"
        >
        Jack Ruby is seen sitting in an office at the Dallas Morning News by 
        newspaper employee Wanda Walker. ref. Crossfire, p 327
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Eddie Piper says he speaks to Oswald"
        >
        TSBD employee Eddie Piper said he actually spoke to Oswald, 
        "Just at twelve o'clock, down on the first floor". 
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:10:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Unidentified cars seen cruising motorcade area"
        >
        Lee Bowers, a railway supervisor located in a tower behind the knoll 
        fence, sees a 1959 Oldsmobile cruise the area. And at 12:20pm, a 
        Black 1957 Ford also did the same and left. Then a third car, a 61 
        or 62 Chevrolet Impala entered the area, parked out of his sight near 
        the decorative masonry wall, then reappeared immediately after the 
        last shot. ref. Crossfire, p 75-76.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:15:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald seen having lunch"
        >
        Carolyn Arnold sees Oswald eating lunch on the second floor lunchroom. 
        "Oswald was sitting in one of the booth seats on the right hand side 
        of the room as you go in. He was alone as usual and appeared to be 
        having lunch. I did not speak to him but I recognized him clearly."
        ref. Crossfire, p 49; Conspiracy - Who Killed Kennedy?, p 108
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:15:00 GMT-0600" end="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:20:00 GMT-0600"
        title="TSBD sixth floor empty"
        >
        TSBD employee Bonnie Ray Williams leaves the sixth floor after eating 
        his lunch, he saw nobody ref. Crossfire, p 49; Conspiracy - Who Killed 
        Kennedy?, p 106
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:15:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Man with rifle seen at Western end of TSBD"
        >
        Witness Arnold Rowland observes man with rifle at the Westeren end 
        of TSBD. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 300
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:18:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Man with seizure in front of TSBD"
        >
        A young man suffers some sort of seizure in front of the book depository.
        ref. Crossfire, p 42
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:19:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Police radio for ambulance"
        >
        Police Radio "code 3" (haste), for ambulance for Dealey Plaza. The 
        ambulance arrived and picked up a suspected epilectic, departing at 
        12:25 pm, and was taken to Parkland Hospital where his admittance 
        was never recorded. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 137
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:20:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Bonnie Ray Williams left 6th floor"
        >
        Bonnie Ray Williams, left the 6th floor after finishing his lunch 
        and using the elevator joined co workers on the 5th floor to watch 
        the motorcade. ref. Crossfire, p 47.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:30:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Kennedy shot"
        >
        President Kennedy shot in Dallas.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:00:00 GMT-0600" end="Fri Nov 22 1963 18:00:00 GMT-0600" isDuration="true"
        title="David Ferrie takes mysterious drive"
        >
        David Ferrie takes a mysterious 364 mile drive in the afternoon.
        ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 131
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:30:40 GMT-0600"
        title="Police radio"
        >
        Police Radio. Bill Decker orders officers to the "Railroad track 
        area just North of Elm." ref, Treachery in Dallas, p 136
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:32:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Washington D.C.'s phone system breakdown"
        >
        Breakdown of Washington D.C.'s telephone system for almost 1 hour.
        (Though Hoover's line remains fuctional?) ref. Conspiracy of Silence, p 71.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:33:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald leaves TSBD and boards bus"
        >
        Lee Harvey Oswald leaves Depository and boards bus. ref. W.C
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:37:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Witness pinpoints window"
        >
        Sergent Harkness reports he has a witness who had pinpointed the window. 
        (Howard Brennan)
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:38:00 GMT-0600"
        title="JFK arrives at Parkland Hospital"
        >
        JFK arrives at Parkland Hospital. ref. Best Evidence, p 710.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:40:00 GMT-0600"
        title="White male seen running from TSBD"
        >
        Police officer Roger Craig sees a white male running down the hill from 
        the direction of the book depository and climbs into a waiting Rambler 
        station wagon and drives off. ref. Crossfire, p. 329
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:40:00 GMT-0600" end="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:45:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald gets off bus and boards taxi"
        >
        Oswald gets off bus and boards second taxi after allowing a woman 
        to take first taxi, talls driver William Whaley, "500 North Beckley 
        Street". ref. WC
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:45:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Description of suspect on police radio"
        >
        Description put out about suspect on Dallas police radio. "The wanted 
        person in this is a slender white male about thirty, five feet ten, 
        one sixty five, carrying what looked to be a 30.30 or some type of 
        Winchester".
        
        Officer Tippit told by H/Q dispatcher to "go to central Oakcliff area".
        ref. Rush to Judgement, p 194.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:48:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Police radio of assassin's location"
        >
        Police Radio in refrence to the location of the assassin. "He is 
        thought to be in the Texas School Book Depository here on the North 
        West corner of Elm and Houston." ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 35
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:49:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Capt Talbert orders to cut off TSBD"
        >
        Capt Talbert giving orders on Police radio. "Have that cut off on 
        the back side will you? Make sure nobody leaves there". 
        (Refering to the Depository). ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 143
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:51:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Homicide Chief William Fritz calls"
        >
        Homicide Cheif William Fritz calls in to the dispatchers office 
        from his post at the Trade Mart to ask if JFK will still be going 
        to the site. He is told, "It's very doubtful." DOH!
        ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 150
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 12:54:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Office Tippit calls H/Q"
        >
        Officer Tippit calls into H/Q, and is asked if he is in Oakcliff 
        area. He replies, "Yes". ref. Rush to Judgement, p.194.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="JFK pronounced dead"
        >
        JFK PRONOUNCED DEAD. ref. Best Evidence, p 710.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Police car outside Oswald's rooming house"
        >
        Police car no 207 stops outside Oswalds rooming house, and sounds horn twice. 
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Bullet discovered"
        >
        Parkland hospital. Darrell Tomlinson discovers the stretcher bullet 
        399 which rolls out from under a mat when stretcher bumps the wall.
        ref. Best Evidence, p 90.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:00:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald seen entering Texas Theater"
        >
        Oswald enters the Texas Theater according to theater assistant 
        manager shortly after 1:00 pm. ref. Crossfire, p 353.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:04:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald seen at bus stop"
        >
        Oswald seen standing at bus stop outside his rooming house by 
        his landlady. ref. Rush to Judgement, p 159.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:05:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Fake Secret Service agent pulled over"
        >
        South of Dallas three men pulled over, one identifies himself as a 
        Secret Service agent and states "We are in a hurry to get to New 
        Orleans to investigate part of the shooting." However there is no 
        record of Secret Service being dispatched to New Orleans on the 
        day of the assassination.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:08:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Officer Tippitt calls H/Q twice"
        >
        Officer Tippitt makes two attempts to call H/Q, but dispatcher does 
        not reply. ref. Rush to Judgement, p 195.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:10:00 GMT-0600"
        title="J.D. Tippit's body discovered"
        >
        T.F..Bewley comes upon J.D Tippit's body in the street. As he gets 
        out to help he looks at his watch, which reads 1:10pm
        ref. Conspiracy - Who Killed Kennedy?, p 122
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:12:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Hulls found on sixth floor of TSBD"
        >
        Policeman Luke Mooney finds hulls on sixth floor of Depository.
        ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 143
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:15:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Oswald inside Texas theatre"
        >
        Oswald buys popcorn at concession stand inside Texas theatre, 
        according to concession stand operator Boroughs.
        ref. Crossfire, p 353.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:16:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Police says Tippit shot"
        >
        Police told "Officer Tippit has been shot." by civilian Domingo 
        Benavides using Tippit's police car radio. ref. Crossfire, p 348.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:20:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Live TV reports shots heard from the Knoll"
        >
        Jean Hill in live television report states she heard shots from 
        the Knoll. ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 153
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:22:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Rifle found on sixth floor of TSBD"
        >
        Rifle found on sixth floor of Book Depository, first identified 
        as 7.5 German Mauser.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:22:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Police radio describing Tippit's killer"
        >
        Police radio call goes out describing Tippit's killer as about 
        30, 5ft 8in black hair and slender. ref. Unanswered Questions, p 105.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:25:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Police reports finding of white jacket"
        >
        Police radio reports finding of a white jacket in parking lot.
        ref. Rush to Judgement, p 191.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:30:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Seth Kantor encounters Jack Ruby at Parkland hospital"
        >
        Seth Kantor encounters Jack Ruby at Parkland hospital and has brief 
        conversation with him. ref. Crossfire, p. 366.
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:35:00 GMT-0600"
        title="TSBD declared secured"
        >
        Police Radio. The TSBD is mentioned, "It's secure now."
        ref. Treachery in Dallas, p 143
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:36:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Police radio from Tippit's murder scene"
        >
        Police Radio from scene of Tippit's murder, "I got an eyeball witness 
        to the getaway man - that suspect in this shooting. He is a white male ... 
        apparently armed with a .32, dark finish automatic pistol..."
        ref. Conspiracy - Who Killed Kennedy?, p 119
        </event>
    <event start="Fri Nov 22 1963 13:45:00 GMT-0600"
        title="Police radio of suspect entering Texas theatre"
        >
        Police Radio "Have information, a suspect just went into Texas theatre 
        on West Jefferson". ref. Unanswered Questions, p 112.
        </event>

</data>